Nikolai Dorofeev

Software Engineer

IT specialist with experience in a wide range of technologies, focusing on Node.js ecosystem. Created web-applications from database and server layers to dynamic Single Page Applications and deployment to hosting.

☑ dorich2000@gmail.com → t.me/d0rich ⊕ d0rich.me c) d0rich in linkedin.com/in/d0rich O Tbilisi, Georgia

Work Experience

Backend Software Engineer Exactpro

Aug 2023 - Present (1 year)

- Contributed to the internal Python framework for testing financial systems.
- Developed tools for reconciling data between different trading protocols.
- · Developed tools for simulating and inspecting trading systems algorithms.
- · Retrospectively analyzed and improved the performance of the existing codebase.
- · Optimized development process by implementation of the versatile parser for the internal file format.

Full-stack Engineer Red-Green Life Design

Nov 2023 - Jul 2024 (9 months)

- Developed a mobile application for tracking diet results using React Native + Expo.
- · Developed backend services for the application using Node.js + Express.
- Configured OAuth2.0 authentication for the application.
- Managed PostgreSQL database for the application.
- Managed backend instances for different stages of product development.
- Configured CI/CD pipeline for the application using GitHub Actions.

DocOps / Full-stack Engineer Exactpro

Jul 2021 - Aug 2023 (2 years 2 months)

- · Developed a custom documentation portal with features for technical writers using Gridsome (Vue.js + GraphQL).
- · Led development of an easy-to-deploy and easy-to-update docs web toolkit package based on Nuxt.js and Tailwind CSS.
- Integrated applications with 3rd party solutions such as GitHub or Algolia.
- Analyzed user requirements to derive technical software design and performance requirements.
- · Developed demonstration Python and Kotlin modules for th2 complex Kubernetes-based microservices framework with gRPC and RabbitMQ communication.

Languages

- · English: Upper-Intermediate
- French: Intermediate
- Russian: Native

Docker

Unix

GitHub actions

Kubernetes

GitLab CI



- Wrote clear and easy-to-understand documentation pages for complex Kubernetes-based - microservices framework.
- Configured CI/CD pipelines for publishing static websites and npm packages via GitHub actions, GitLab CI, Jenkins.
- Mentored junior specialists and technical writers.
- Developed #1 architecture for providing traceability of digital assets between blockchains for Swift Hackathon 2022.

Projects	
	
ertificates	
	Course Page
Certificate Verify Certificate	
Certificate	
_	
Certificate	

Education

Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Systems and Technologies in Business Tomsk Polytechnic University

Sep 2018 - Jul 2022 (3 years 11 months)

This program is aimed at training specialists in the field of information systems and technologies in business, who are able to solve problems of business management and economic activity using modern information technologies and systems. Projects were related to the development of ecommerce systems and integration with ERP systems.

Main learning stack: ASP.NET + MS SQL.

However, students was free to choose any technology stack for their projects.

Used technologies: Node.js, Python Flask, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Docker, etc.

Diploma project: distributed full-stack framework for trading automation implemented with Node.js and Vue.js.